<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Phones - Tag - Shallow and Pedantic</title><link>https://lutzky.net/tags/phones/</link><description>Phones - Tag - Shallow and Pedantic</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>lutzky@gmail.com (Ohad Lutzky)</managingEditor><webMaster>lutzky@gmail.com (Ohad Lutzky)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 16:58:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lutzky.net/tags/phones/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SMS and why it annoys me</title><link>https://lutzky.net/posts/sms-and-why-it-annoys-me/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 16:58:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Ohad Lutzky</author><guid>https://lutzky.net/posts/sms-and-why-it-annoys-me/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Don&rsquo;t get me wrong. I love being able to communicate textually with friends,
coworkers and family. It&rsquo;s ideal for a noisy pub; a somewhat-private
conversation on a crowded bus; telling something to someone who may be asleep,
so they see it first thing when they wake up; making quick responses while in a
meeting without being rude (well, at least at my workplace it&rsquo;s considered
perfectly acceptable). It&rsquo;s also very handy when you want to tell someone
something they ought to write down, such as a phone number or something they
should remember to buy. My problem isn&rsquo;t with the concept of mobile textual
messaging - it&rsquo;s with SMS, the &ldquo;Short Message Service&rdquo;, as provided by Israeli
carriers (and possibly worldwide).</p>
<p>The first problem I&rsquo;d like to discuss is length. SMS messages are limited to
160 characters, or rather - 160 bytes. If your message includes any foreign
characters, such as Hebrew letters, then UTF-16 mode takes effect, and your
message is limited to 70 characters, which is ridiculously short. While the
name of the service, SMS, implies that the messages should indeed be short,
this is not the only common usage: If you want to have an actual conversation
with someone (and this is a perfectly reasonable situation), messages will be
longer than 160 characters, and certainly longer than 70. The problem becomes
worse if u dont want to use shorthands n skip punctuations like many smsers do.
(Ever found yourself about to send a 75-character message, going over it to
find 5 characters to trim without looking like an idiot?)</p>
<p>There have been several attempts to overcome the short-message problem, all of
them implemented as workarounds in cellphone software. The initial, primitive
approach was to simply split a message up into appropriately-sized chunks, and
send out those chunks as separate messages: A 150-character Hebrew message
would be sent out as 3 separate messages (70, 70, 10 characters respectively).
Later on, a mechanism was invented for the phones to detect the split messages,
stitch them back up on the recipient&rsquo;s phone, and notify the recipient if the
message is incomplete. Poor man&rsquo;s TCP.</p>
<p>The split-message solution is very problematic, especially when taking into
account two other problems with SMS: Reliability and price. The reliability
problem is subtle: SMS message <em>usually</em> make it across, but when they don&rsquo;t
(and sometimes, in fact, they don&rsquo;t), no notification is given. Where E-mail
servers notify you about delivery failure, where instant messaging services
tell you that the other party has disconnected, SMS has&hellip; nothing. There&rsquo;s no
way to know that your message hasn&rsquo;t been received, unless a little-known,
not-supported-everywhere and highly annoying &ldquo;read receipt&rdquo; feature is enabled.</p>
<p>The price problem is completely absurd: I have a small 1GB plan at Orange,
which costs 70₪/month. That&rsquo;s 70 NIS / 1GB, 1GB being 109 bytes. That comes to
7 &amp;times 10-6 Agorot per byte. Suppose that an SMS-style service would need a
bloated 100-byte header, so an SMS message is 260 bytes. Therefore, an SMS
message should cost 0.00182 Agorot. In reality, it costs 44 Agorot
(inter-carrier average) without a plan, or 14 Agorot (at best, requiring a
1000-SMS plan) with a plan. That&rsquo;s between 7692× and 24176× as much.</p>
<p>One additional problem with SMS is the fact that they&rsquo;re locked into your
device. Got a new phone? You have to go through a very complicated process to
transfer your SMS messages over, and this isn&rsquo;t possible for every phone. Lost
your old phone? Unless you were backing up manually, your messages are gone.
Have a separate work-phone? You&rsquo;ll need to use each phone to see messages sent
specifically to it. None of these problems occur with an online E-mail
provider, why should they happen with mobile texting?</p>
<p>With modern phones, sending and receiving E-mail is just as easy as sending and
receiving SMS messages. The main problem is that not everyone has a modern
phone, and E-mail on older phones is quite cumbersome. Worse yet, older phones
don&rsquo;t immediately notify you of E-mails. There could be some good money in
creating an E-mail-to-SMS gateway - and it would be quite convenient to use if
done properly. Imagine having your SMS messages united with your E-mails,
organized and searchable by your favorite E-mail client. If you have a modern
phone with proper E-mail notification and sending abilities, this could be very
handy. Just sayin'.</p>
<p><strong>Addendum:</strong> It seems that <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zpgMJ7Hv6tk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Google Voice</a> already does exactly
what I want, but is not available in Israel. Thanks, Shachar.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Android</title><link>https://lutzky.net/posts/android/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2010 09:26:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Ohad Lutzky</author><guid>https://lutzky.net/posts/android/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve finally gotten the chance to get one of those newfangled Android phones.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve recently &ldquo;bought&rdquo; a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Samsung_Galaxy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Samsung Galaxy
Android</a> phone (the older i7500,
not the newer i9000 &ldquo;S&rdquo;) model. It&rsquo;s a seriously serious upgrade from my old
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nokia_6120_classic" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Nokia 6120 Classic</a>, and as I
broke the 6120&rsquo;s screen and reverted back to my trusty old <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nokia_6070" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Nokia
6070</a> (which I couldn&rsquo;t even get to
run the GMail app), I was quite a happy camper switching to a modern phone.</p>
<p>The whole idea of Android has always been very appealing to me - Nokia&rsquo;s
software has been declining in quality, and while Motorola and Samsung have
always made excellent hardware, they could never get the knack of good
software. Google has. Problem solved, right?</p>
<p>The Android software is miles ahead of anything I&rsquo;ve ever seen, including
iPhone. I now have connectivity everywhere, and apps to sync all of my favorite
things - GMail and Google Calendar are included, GTasks is great for tasks,
Paperdroid is great for Read It Later, NewsRob is great for Google Reader. The
Facebook and Twidroyd applications are also quite nice, and the convenience has
me using those networks more. I even have nifty stuff like Transdroid, a
Transmission web client which is actually very good at <strong>adding</strong> torrents
while I&rsquo;m away, so they&rsquo;re done by the time I get home. I get my reading done
with Aldiko and ACV (for comics). Even Israeli sites have some good
applications up, such as YNet and <a href="http://d.co.il/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Dapei Zahav</a> have a nice
Android app, though not as nice as their iPhone ones. And of course, there&rsquo;s
the wonderful <a href="http://waze.co.il/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Waze</a>, which is the most Israeli solution to
the road congestion problem I&rsquo;ve ever seen. I&rsquo;ve even had the chance to do some
on-foot navigation with Google Maps, which is also handy.</p>
<p>The phone itself has a beautiful AMOLED screen, great audio quality (comes with
quite a good set of headphones as well), and looks sleek. The touchscreen is
responsive enough (though not anywhere near new Android devices nor the
iPhone/iPod touch), and it even comes with a free extra 8GB SD card, for a
total of 16GB.</p>
<p>And now, to rant.</p>
<p>Battery life isn&rsquo;t what is should be - the phone is awesome, I want to use it,
and it can barely get through the day - especially if I&rsquo;m doing heavy stuff
like Waze (GPS + Data + screen is always on + voice), but even if I&rsquo;m just
surfing casually. The unlock button is located inconveniently on the bottom
part of the right side, just above the camera button. The home button is
located between the Back and Send buttons, meaning it&rsquo;s very easy to hit by
accident; it&rsquo;s not even labeled. The CPU isn&rsquo;t always fast enough to keep
everything completely smooth, and while this is generally acceptable, it gets
rather irksome in odd places: If you turn on screen auto-rotation (which uses
more battery power), rotation takes a while and might be accidental. However,
there is no <em>manual</em> screen rotation option as far as I can tell.</p>
<p>As a music player (relating to my previous post), the device works well enough -
but I couldn&rsquo;t, for the life of me, get Hebrew support in ID3 tags (no matter
what the encoding is), and only a limited subset of ID3 tag versions is
supported, and everything works much better with Ogg files.</p>
<p>The flaws I&rsquo;ve mentioned are relatively minor and nitpicky - for Waze, you can
use the car charger (which comes with the phone, thankfully). The buttons are
OK after some getting used to (and installing the excellent AnySoftKeyboard),
and operation is generally smooth. However, there is a major issue I can&rsquo;t wrap
my head around - the shipped firmware is 1.5 cupcake, and there are absolutely
zero updates available from Samsung. There is a semi-official leaked 1.6 update
which, as I&rsquo;ve heard, is quite buggy. An awesome guy called
<a href="http://www.drakaz.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">drakaz</a> has been working on a Froyo (2.2) port for the
Galaxy, which I really should check out, but Samsung&rsquo;s behavior on this topic
is inexcusable in my opinion.</p>
<p>All-in-all, however, I&rsquo;m happy with my phone. It&rsquo;s a joy to use, and the price
is hard to beat - free with my phone plan, provided I can rake up a bill of
150₪ (which I can, with some help from the 70₪ 1GB data plan, which comes in
quite handy). My next phone will, however, probably not be a Samsung.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Broken phone screen - data rescue</title><link>https://lutzky.net/posts/broken-phone-screen-data-rescue/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2009 02:32:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Ohad Lutzky</author><guid>https://lutzky.net/posts/broken-phone-screen-data-rescue/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Last weekend I broke my Nokia 6120&rsquo;s screen. I have a military phone, which is
far cheaper, so I&rsquo;ve decided to keep it offline. However, being the sentimental
guy that I am, I did want to save all of my contacts and SMS messages (in
addition to the photos, which presented less of a problem). This proved to be a
bit of a challenge without the screen working.</p>
<p>Usually, when you connect the phone via USB, it asks if you want &ldquo;PC Suite
mode&rdquo; or &ldquo;Data Transfer mode&rdquo;. The &ldquo;Data Transfer&rdquo; mode has the phone show up
as a standard USB storage device, which allows for easy transfer of MP3 files,
photos and videos to and from the phone, without any nokia-specific software.
However, it only works for the external SD card, so you can&rsquo;t use that to
access SMS messages or contacts.</p>
<p>I usually only need &ldquo;Data Transfer&rdquo; mode, so I changed the default to that.
Today I regret that decision, as it cost me a couple of hours&rsquo; work. I called
the Orange hotline, and they did their best to help me, including trying to
blind-guide me through the menus, which failed because the menus are actually
dynamic and I didn&rsquo;t have the default setup. They actually got me 90% of the
way there - here&rsquo;s the solution I found: Hit the red (disconnect) button, and
type the Soft Reset GSM code: <code>*#7780#</code>. Now press the &ldquo;left menu&rdquo; key (not the
left key, nor the menu key - the left of the two &ldquo;dynamic&rdquo; keys) - this part
was what the Orange hotline missed, because it seemed so obvious. Then hit
12345 (this is the default &ldquo;secret code&rdquo;), and the left menu key again. I found
this by watching a demo of the soft reset on YouTube.</p>
<p>At this point I used VirtualBox and the Nokia PC suite (both are
free-as-in-beer) to do the heavy lifting. I now have a text file with all of my
contacts, a CSV file with all of my SMS messages, and all of my images saved
both to my computer and a DR site. Now I just need to upgrade my military phone
(Mirs)&hellip;</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Whatever happened to black &amp;amp; white LCDs?</title><link>https://lutzky.net/posts/whatever-happened-to-black-white-lcds/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2008 11:58:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Ohad Lutzky</author><guid>https://lutzky.net/posts/whatever-happened-to-black-white-lcds/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I had a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Game_boy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Game Boy</a> once. I could play it
just about anywhere, and battery life - for the time - was great. I lost it at
one point, and replaced it with a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Game_gear" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Game
Gear</a>, which sucked the life out of 6
AA batteries rather quickly. The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Game_Boy_Color" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Game Boy
Color</a> was actually decent on
battery life, but since it didn&rsquo;t have a backlight, you had to play it at very
specific angles.</p>
<p>For gaming, I can appreciate the need for a color screen. My point has to do
with cellphones. True, most cellphones today come with cameras, are able to
play video, and are rather capable mobile gaming platforms (when compared to
the Game Boy, that is). All this does, in fact, require a color screen.
However, I believe that there is a market for cellphones which do not support
these features, but do support neat things like 3G internet connectivity (GMail
and RSS on the phone is a major Win, in my opinion), and have a comfortable SMS
interface. These features actually suffer from having a color screen: Battery
life (for the powerful backlight), viewing angle, and screen resolution take a
hit. While it&rsquo;s true that color LCDs have come a long way since the Game Gear,
so have black &amp; white display technologies (E-Paper, anyone?).</p>
<p>Of course, my wish for a modern B&amp;W-screen cellphone will likely never come
true. The simple reason is that they would be totally unmarketable. Even
business-types like color screens nowadays. So I&rsquo;ll just keep holding out for a
folding E-Paper mobile browser.</p>
]]></description></item></channel></rss>