<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>hardware on Shallow and Pedantic</title><link>https://lutzky.net/tags/hardware/</link><description>Recent content in hardware on Shallow and Pedantic</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lutzky.net/tags/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PiTemp</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2021/03/14/pitemp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2021/03/14/pitemp/</guid><description>An adventure with Raspberry Pi, Golang, and small displays.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I had been looking for an excuse to mess around with Raspberry Pi for a while, and found one: I wanted a graph of temperature and humidity over time, and - while we&rsquo;re at it - a nice display of those two. Technically speaking, I already have a Nest thermostat which should provide those, but it won&rsquo;t display humidity and there&rsquo;s no easy way to get a graph off it (besides, then I&rsquo;d need another excuse for messing around with a Pi).</p>
<p>The code for the final result is in <a href="https://github.com/lutzky/pitemp">https://github.com/lutzky/pitemp</a>.</p>
<h1 id="stage-1-lcd-and-dht">Stage 1: LCD and DHT</h1>
<p>Hardware:</p>
<ul>
<li>A <a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/products/raspberry-pi-zero-w/">Raspberry Pi Zero W</a> a friend gave me (that&rsquo;ll become important later on)</li>
<li>A <a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B07L83K6CF">DHT11</a> temperature &amp; humidity sensor</li>
<li>A <a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B07QNKCLJM">4x20 character LCD</a>; apparently an HD44780 controller or compatible.</li>
</ul>
<p>This was my first time coding for hardware on the raspberry pi, and it went fairly well.</p>
<h1 id="lcd-quirks">LCD quirks</h1>
<p>Getting the degree symbol (°, ASCII <code>0xb0</code>) was a bit of a challenge. While the official HD44780 spec shows it should be available with &ldquo;ROM Code A02&rdquo; (i.e. Latin mode), it&rsquo;s not clear if this can be toggled in software, and the characters my unit displayed matched &ldquo;ROM Code A00&rdquo; (Japanese)&hellip; mostly, that is. Some characters were malformed, and the <a href="https://github.com/d2r2/go-hd44780">unofficial library I used</a> didn&rsquo;t support custom characters (which the hardware seems to support). Fortunately, the Japanese ROM code had a Handakuten symbol (ﾟ, like the circle from ぽ but as a separate character), which is close enough.</p>
<p>The LCD was also quite slow to refresh, the way I was using it; any faster than 1 hz would lead to corruption, meaning that the &ldquo;second-by-second&rdquo; clock display I wanted wasn&rsquo;t feasible.</p>
<p>Finally, the LCD unit is much, <em>much</em> large than the Raspberry Pi Zero, and has to be wired awkwardly to it. With some covid-lockdown-induced creativity, a twist tie, and a bit of sewing thread (!), I turned the box it came in into a &ldquo;case&rdquo;.</p>
<p><a href="/assets/images/2021/03/pitemp/lcd_box.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/2021/03/pitemp/lcd_box.jpg" alt="LCD Box"  />
</a></p>
<h1 id="cross-compilation">Cross compilation</h1>
<p>While the Pi Zero is certainly <em>capable</em> of being a fully-fledged Go development environment, it&rsquo;s not a fast one (and me using a cheap old SD card isn&rsquo;t helping). I got a much faster edit-compile-run loop by working on my main laptop, cross-compiling for ARM, and <code>scp</code>-ing the result over. That&rsquo;s despite Go&rsquo;s hefty statically-build binaries (7-12MB for these, depending on stripping).</p>
<p>Cross compiling is done like so (e.g. in a <a href="https://github.com/lutzky/pitemp/blob/main/build.sh">convenience script</a>):</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-shell" data-lang="shell">$ sudo apt install gcc-arm-linux-gnueabi
$ <span class="nb">export</span> <span class="nv">CC</span><span class="o">=</span>arm-linux-gnueabi-gcc <span class="nv">CGO_ENABLED</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="m">1</span> <span class="nv">GOOS</span><span class="o">=</span>linux <span class="nv">GOARM</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="m">6</span> <span class="nv">GOARCH</span><span class="o">=</span>arm
$ go -o main.arm build main.go
</code></pre></div><p>For build-and-run-on-save, this can be used with <code>entr</code>. However, because you can&rsquo;t modify an executable file as it runs (in this case), you need to use a temporary file. On my laptop, I run:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-shell" data-lang="shell">$ find <span class="p">|</span> entr -c -s <span class="s2">&#34;./build.sh &amp;&amp; scp main.arm TARGET-MACHINE:main.arm.new
</span></code></pre></div><p>Then, on the pi, I run:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-shell" data-lang="shell">$ ls main.arm.new <span class="p">|</span> sudo entr -r -c -s <span class="s2">&#34;cp main.arm.new main &amp;&amp; exec ./main&#34;</span>
</code></pre></div><h1 id="stage-2-pioled">Stage 2: PiOLED</h1>
<p>I looked for a not-so-ridiculously-large display, and found <a href="https://www.adafruit.com/product/3527">adafruit&rsquo;s PiOLED</a> to be perfect. Its HAT form factor makes for a much tidier device, and the display itself is reminiscent of the 2007 Sansa Clip m300 (albeit monochromatic). Library support is also much better, thanks to <a href="http://periph.io">http://periph.io</a>.</p>
<p>That being said, my friend soldered the Pi&rsquo;s pins on &ldquo;downwards&rdquo;, as this is apparently more convenient when using it on a breadboard. I figured it&rsquo;s time to order my own Pi Zero (you can get them with the pins pre-soldered, facing &ldquo;up&rdquo;); I later found that <a href="https://pkg.go.dev/periph.io/x/devices/v3/ssd1306#Opts">this might be configurable</a>, but it&rsquo;d still be pretty awkward.</p>
<p>The PiOLED library (actually periph.io&rsquo;s ssd1306 library) essentially lets you render an <code>image.Image</code>; since these are also trivially renderable to PNG, I could speed up development even further by adding an HTTP endpoint to serve the current image, even if the hardware isn&rsquo;t present; this also let me zoom into the rendered image instead of squinting at the actual display, making it easier to align things pixel-by-pixel. I eventually ended up separating the code into two binaries - <code>pitemp</code> would communicate with the sensors and provide an HTTP endpoint, whereas <code>pitemp_pioled</code> (and <code>pitemp_lcd</code>) would communicate with <code>pitemp</code> and the physical display (or run in <code>--simulator</code> mode on my laptop, for HTTP-endpoint-only rendering).</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m quite happy with the final result:</p>
<p><a href="/assets/images/2021/03/pitemp/pioled.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/assets/images/2021/03/pitemp/pioled.jpg" alt="PiOLED PiTemp"  />
</a></p>
<p>Happy hacking!</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>DD-WRT awesomeness</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2010/11/20/dd-wrt-awesomeness/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2010/11/20/dd-wrt-awesomeness/</guid><description>Since I&amp;rsquo;ve last posted, I&amp;rsquo;ve moved to a new apartment. First order of business - get a working internet connection. This is extra-challenging when your primary machine doesn&amp;rsquo;t even have a wireless network card.
My first hack used my trusty laptop - it has a properly working wireless card, and could connect to my roommate&amp;rsquo;s router quite easily. It runs Ubuntu, and as it turns out, that means sharing the connection was dead-simple: Right-click on the network manager icon, add a new wired connection called &amp;ldquo;Shared&amp;rdquo;, and under IPv4 settings, choose &amp;ldquo;Shared to other computers&amp;rdquo;.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Since I&rsquo;ve last posted, I&rsquo;ve moved to a new apartment. First order of business -
get a working internet connection. This is extra-challenging when your
primary machine doesn&rsquo;t even have a wireless network card.</p>
<p>My first hack used my trusty laptop - it has a properly working wireless card,
and could connect to my roommate&rsquo;s router quite easily. It runs Ubuntu, and as
it turns out, that means sharing the connection was dead-simple: Right-click on
the network manager icon, add a new wired connection called &ldquo;Shared&rdquo;, and under
IPv4 settings, choose &ldquo;Shared to other computers&rdquo;. That&rsquo;s it. Once I connected
my desktop to my laptop, it automatically got all of its settings, and I was
good to go.</p>
<p>However, this was kind of annoying - I had to leave my laptop on, the reception
in my room isn&rsquo;t perfect so it would sometimes disconnect (requiring manual
intervention), and my laptop wasn&rsquo;t free for ordinary use (if I wanted my
torrents to keep going).</p>
<p>The solution: I grabbed my (horrible) old D-Link DIR-300 router, and installed
DD-WRT on it. This gave it an awesome &ldquo;client mode&rdquo; feature, which allowed it
to use it the same way I used my laptop to bridge my wireless connection.
Flashing it worked quite well by following the guide (the updated version in
the wiki, that is - it has proper instructions for connecting to RedBoot, the
D-Link flashing interface, from Linux), and another guide helped me set up
Client mode. All seems well, except for two issues:</p>
<p>First, port forwarding doesn&rsquo;t seem to work properly - it works well on the
internal network (that is, I can SSH into my desktop using my laptop), but not
on the internet (SSH port shows up as open, but I can&rsquo;t connect). I&rsquo;m also
guessing that UPnP/NAT-PMP won&rsquo;t work properly. Second, and this is an old
problem - the router has a high-pitched whine. This may have something to do
with the fact that the AC/DC adapter it came with is rated for 12V @ 1A,
whereas the router is rated 5V @ 1.2A. Let&rsquo;s hope it doesn&rsquo;t fry (hasn&rsquo;t for
the 3 years I used it).</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Android</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2010/09/04/android/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2010/09/04/android/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve finally gotten the chance to get one of those newfangled Android phones.
I&amp;rsquo;ve recently &amp;ldquo;bought&amp;rdquo; a Samsung Galaxy Android phone (the older i7500, not the newer i9000 &amp;ldquo;S&amp;rdquo;) model. It&amp;rsquo;s a seriously serious upgrade from my old Nokia 6120 Classic, and as I broke the 6120&amp;rsquo;s screen and reverted back to my trusty old Nokia 6070 (which I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even get to run the GMail app), I was quite a happy camper switching to a modern phone.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve finally gotten the chance to get one of those newfangled Android phones.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve recently &ldquo;bought&rdquo; a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Samsung_Galaxy">Samsung Galaxy
Android</a> phone (the older i7500,
not the newer i9000 &ldquo;S&rdquo;) model. It&rsquo;s a seriously serious upgrade from my old
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nokia_6120_classic">Nokia 6120 Classic</a>, and as I
broke the 6120&rsquo;s screen and reverted back to my trusty old <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nokia_6070">Nokia
6070</a> (which I couldn&rsquo;t even get to
run the GMail app), I was quite a happy camper switching to a modern phone.</p>
<p>The whole idea of Android has always been very appealing to me - Nokia&rsquo;s
software has been declining in quality, and while Motorola and Samsung have
always made excellent hardware, they could never get the knack of good
software. Google has. Problem solved, right?</p>
<p>The Android software is miles ahead of anything I&rsquo;ve ever seen, including
iPhone. I now have connectivity everywhere, and apps to sync all of my favorite
things - GMail and Google Calendar are included, GTasks is great for tasks,
Paperdroid is great for Read It Later, NewsRob is great for Google Reader. The
Facebook and Twidroyd applications are also quite nice, and the convenience has
me using those networks more. I even have nifty stuff like Transdroid, a
Transmission web client which is actually very good at <strong>adding</strong> torrents
while I&rsquo;m away, so they&rsquo;re done by the time I get home. I get my reading done
with Aldiko and ACV (for comics). Even Israeli sites have some good
applications up, such as YNet and <a href="http://d.co.il/">Dapei Zahav</a> have a nice
Android app, though not as nice as their iPhone ones. And of course, there&rsquo;s
the wonderful <a href="http://waze.co.il/">Waze</a>, which is the most Israeli solution to
the road congestion problem I&rsquo;ve ever seen. I&rsquo;ve even had the chance to do some
on-foot navigation with Google Maps, which is also handy.</p>
<p>The phone itself has a beautiful AMOLED screen, great audio quality (comes with
quite a good set of headphones as well), and looks sleek. The touchscreen is
responsive enough (though not anywhere near new Android devices nor the
iPhone/iPod touch), and it even comes with a free extra 8GB SD card, for a
total of 16GB.</p>
<p>And now, to rant.</p>
<p>Battery life isn&rsquo;t what is should be - the phone is awesome, I want to use it,
and it can barely get through the day - especially if I&rsquo;m doing heavy stuff
like Waze (GPS + Data + screen is always on + voice), but even if I&rsquo;m just
surfing casually. The unlock button is located inconveniently on the bottom
part of the right side, just above the camera button. The home button is
located between the Back and Send buttons, meaning it&rsquo;s very easy to hit by
accident; it&rsquo;s not even labeled. The CPU isn&rsquo;t always fast enough to keep
everything completely smooth, and while this is generally acceptable, it gets
rather irksome in odd places: If you turn on screen auto-rotation (which uses
more battery power), rotation takes a while and might be accidental. However,
there is no <em>manual</em> screen rotation option as far as I can tell.</p>
<p>As a music player (relating to my previous post), the device works well enough -
but I couldn&rsquo;t, for the life of me, get Hebrew support in ID3 tags (no matter
what the encoding is), and only a limited subset of ID3 tag versions is
supported, and everything works much better with Ogg files.</p>
<p>The flaws I&rsquo;ve mentioned are relatively minor and nitpicky - for Waze, you can
use the car charger (which comes with the phone, thankfully). The buttons are
OK after some getting used to (and installing the excellent AnySoftKeyboard),
and operation is generally smooth. However, there is a major issue I can&rsquo;t wrap
my head around - the shipped firmware is 1.5 cupcake, and there are absolutely
zero updates available from Samsung. There is a semi-official leaked 1.6 update
which, as I&rsquo;ve heard, is quite buggy. An awesome guy called
<a href="http://www.drakaz.com/">drakaz</a> has been working on a Froyo (2.2) port for the
Galaxy, which I really should check out, but Samsung&rsquo;s behavior on this topic
is inexcusable in my opinion.</p>
<p>All-in-all, however, I&rsquo;m happy with my phone. It&rsquo;s a joy to use, and the price
is hard to beat - free with my phone plan, provided I can rake up a bill of
150₪ (which I can, with some help from the 70₪ 1GB data plan, which comes in
quite handy). My next phone will, however, probably not be a Samsung.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>My music player has sunk</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2010/03/13/my-music-player-has-sunk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2010/03/13/my-music-player-has-sunk/</guid><description>My Meizu Mini M6 has died a tragic death as a result of being left in my shirt pocket, which in turn was - with the rest of my shirt - in the laundry. I&amp;rsquo;ve had it for three years, so this would be a good time to review.
My favorite thing about the Mini was the cost. When I bought it, it was far cheaper than comparable players, at ~400₪ for 8GB.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Meizu_M6_miniPlayer">Meizu Mini M6</a> has died a
tragic death as a result of being left in my shirt pocket, which in turn was -
with the rest of my shirt - in the laundry. I&rsquo;ve had it for three years, so
this would be a good time to review.</p>
<p>My favorite thing about the Mini was the cost. When I bought it, it was far
cheaper than comparable players, at ~400₪ for 8GB. For a player with good video
support, it was a steal. Other pros it had include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Great screen. I used to watch TV shows on it quite a bit</li>
<li>Great audio quality, especially in the lower range - very important for a
bass guitarist</li>
<li>Perfect OS compatibility - shows up as a Mass Storage device, just drag your
files over. This is also how firmware upgrades are performed</li>
<li>EBook reader, of sorts</li>
<li>Quite small and very thin</li>
</ul>
<p>However, the player is full of quirks:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Slow startup time. This is compounded by the fact that to turn it on, you
have to press the &ldquo;Play&rdquo; button for about 3 seconds - too much less or too
much more, and it won&rsquo;t start up.</p>
<p>This is even worse when unplugging it from USB - it would rebuild the library
every time, even if you were just charging it.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>You can&rsquo;t turn the player on when it&rsquo;s connected to USB. When it&rsquo;s off,
connecting it to USB is for charging only - to access the filesystem, you
have to disconnect it, turn it on, and connect it again. (&hellip;not that the
player is functional when in it&rsquo;s plugged in&hellip;)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>A few podcast niceties would be very easy to implement and extremely helpful.
There&rsquo;s no way to separate podcasts from the rest of the music, so you don&rsquo;t
get &ldquo;This Week In Tech&rdquo; when you put it on &ldquo;All Music at random&rdquo; mode.  Also,
the player doesn&rsquo;t keep track of positions within audio streams, other than
the last played one.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>There&rsquo;s no way to delete a song from within the player.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The interface is very inconsistent, with the video and audio sections having
completely different key bindings. Long presses and short presses have very
different meanings (but the length isn&rsquo;t all that different), so you have to
be very careful.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Pressing various key during startup had interesting, non-obvious effects,
such as rebuilding the music library or <strong>formatting the player without
asking for confirmation</strong>. This isn&rsquo;t in the official documentation, and even
if it were - that&rsquo;s a <strong>very</strong> bad misfeature.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The newer version of the player, which I have, did away with the bottom
&ldquo;play&rdquo; button, and moved it to the bottom of the 4-way D-pad, instead of the
&ldquo;Enter&rdquo; key. The &ldquo;Enter&rdquo; key was replaced with a tap on the d-pad.
Unfortunately, such a tap is very similar to a volume change drag, and even
if it weren&rsquo;t - is very easy to perform by accident.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>One more feature that I would have liked is one I&rsquo;ve only seen in the iPod
(which I despise for a variety of reasons) - the iPod keeps track of which
songs you&rsquo;ve played all the way through, and remembers that you &ldquo;like&rdquo; them -
this information is later used when building playlists, and is integrated into
iTunes playlists as well.</p>
<p>Now, I might be going to a long course soon, one which will specifically mean
plenty of bus time. So go ahead, guys - recommend a player. :)</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Broken phone screen - data rescue</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2009/10/31/broken-phone-screen-data-rescue/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2009/10/31/broken-phone-screen-data-rescue/</guid><description>Last weekend I broke my Nokia 6120&amp;rsquo;s screen. I have a military phone, which is far cheaper, so I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to keep it offline. However, being the sentimental guy that I am, I did want to save all of my contacts and SMS messages (in addition to the photos, which presented less of a problem). This proved to be a bit of a challenge without the screen working.
Usually, when you connect the phone via USB, it asks if you want &amp;ldquo;PC Suite mode&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Data Transfer mode&amp;rdquo;.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last weekend I broke my Nokia 6120&rsquo;s screen. I have a military phone, which is
far cheaper, so I&rsquo;ve decided to keep it offline. However, being the sentimental
guy that I am, I did want to save all of my contacts and SMS messages (in
addition to the photos, which presented less of a problem). This proved to be a
bit of a challenge without the screen working.</p>
<p>Usually, when you connect the phone via USB, it asks if you want &ldquo;PC Suite
mode&rdquo; or &ldquo;Data Transfer mode&rdquo;. The &ldquo;Data Transfer&rdquo; mode has the phone show up
as a standard USB storage device, which allows for easy transfer of MP3 files,
photos and videos to and from the phone, without any nokia-specific software.
However, it only works for the external SD card, so you can&rsquo;t use that to
access SMS messages or contacts.</p>
<p>I usually only need &ldquo;Data Transfer&rdquo; mode, so I changed the default to that.
Today I regret that decision, as it cost me a couple of hours' work. I called
the Orange hotline, and they did their best to help me, including trying to
blind-guide me through the menus, which failed because the menus are actually
dynamic and I didn&rsquo;t have the default setup. They actually got me 90% of the
way there - here&rsquo;s the solution I found: Hit the red (disconnect) button, and
type the Soft Reset GSM code: <code>*#7780#</code>. Now press the &ldquo;left menu&rdquo; key (not the
left key, nor the menu key - the left of the two &ldquo;dynamic&rdquo; keys) - this part
was what the Orange hotline missed, because it seemed so obvious. Then hit
12345 (this is the default &ldquo;secret code&rdquo;), and the left menu key again. I found
this by watching a demo of the soft reset on YouTube.</p>
<p>At this point I used VirtualBox and the Nokia PC suite (both are
free-as-in-beer) to do the heavy lifting. I now have a text file with all of my
contacts, a CSV file with all of my SMS messages, and all of my images saved
both to my computer and a DR site. Now I just need to upgrade my military phone
(Mirs)&hellip;</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Hardware doesn't like me</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2009/02/26/hardware-doesnt-like-me/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2009/02/26/hardware-doesnt-like-me/</guid><description>Whenever I try messing with hardware at home, inexplicable failures ensue. Especially when trying to help others; no good deed goes unpunished.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m a software kind of guy. Here&rsquo;s proof.</p>
<p>Today I went to visit my grandparents, and it turned out their computer
wouldn&rsquo;t boot. BIOS would load up fine, and I could browse the menus fine - but
once it tried to go on from there, it would simply blink what looked like half
a cursor (that is, half of a <code>_</code>-style cursor). I figured it might be the HDD -
so I took it home, and decided to connect it to my own box. Upon disconnecting
my DVD drive, I destroyed the SATA cord - it had an annoying little metal tab
which had to be pushed in before it would release, and it just wouldn&rsquo;t give,
and the connector just broke, exposing and bending the wires.</p>
<p>Checking if the computer still boots, the BIOS took much longer to display hard
drive status, and while Ubuntu would start booting, it would fail in the
process and tell me that my root hard drive (by UUID) isn&rsquo;t available. Looking
at dmesg, the ata2 module was indeed reporting that the hard drive was too
slow - but a few seconds later it would finally access the drive, and mount
properly. This problem, however, disappeared once I connected my grandparents'
drive! (Mounting it would fail, telling me that I either have a hardware error
or need to connect it to a Windows machine, which I don&rsquo;t have, and run some
diagnostic commands). Sure enough, when the HDD is connected by itself, it gets
quite flaky, but once I connect a second drive (back to the DVD, eventually),
everything works properly. This probably has to do with the fact that both
drives are connected on continuations of the same power cord - but I&rsquo;ve never
experienced such a problem, where you <em>must</em> connect devices to <em>both</em>
connectors on the power cord. A hardware guy I know says he&rsquo;s never heard of
such a problem either.</p>
<p>Naturally, these things never happen when I mess with hardware at work, where
there are plenty of spare parts&hellip;</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Whatever happened to black &amp;amp; white LCDs?</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2008/11/22/whatever-happened-to-black-white-lcds/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2008/11/22/whatever-happened-to-black-white-lcds/</guid><description>I had a Game Boy once. I could play it just about anywhere, and battery life - for the time - was great. I lost it at one point, and replaced it with a Game Gear, which sucked the life out of 6 AA batteries rather quickly. The Game Boy Color was actually decent on battery life, but since it didn&amp;rsquo;t have a backlight, you had to play it at very specific angles.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I had a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Game_boy">Game Boy</a> once. I could play it
just about anywhere, and battery life - for the time - was great. I lost it at
one point, and replaced it with a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Game_gear">Game
Gear</a>, which sucked the life out of 6
AA batteries rather quickly. The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Game_Boy_Color">Game Boy
Color</a> was actually decent on
battery life, but since it didn&rsquo;t have a backlight, you had to play it at very
specific angles.</p>
<p>For gaming, I can appreciate the need for a color screen. My point has to do
with cellphones. True, most cellphones today come with cameras, are able to
play video, and are rather capable mobile gaming platforms (when compared to
the Game Boy, that is). All this does, in fact, require a color screen.
However, I believe that there is a market for cellphones which do not support
these features, but do support neat things like 3G internet connectivity (GMail
and RSS on the phone is a major Win, in my opinion), and have a comfortable SMS
interface. These features actually suffer from having a color screen: Battery
life (for the powerful backlight), viewing angle, and screen resolution take a
hit. While it&rsquo;s true that color LCDs have come a long way since the Game Gear,
so have black &amp; white display technologies (E-Paper, anyone?).</p>
<p>Of course, my wish for a modern B&amp;W-screen cellphone will likely never come
true. The simple reason is that they would be totally unmarketable. Even
business-types like color screens nowadays. So I&rsquo;ll just keep holding out for a
folding E-Paper mobile browser.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Nokia 6120 Classic</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2008/02/11/nokia-6120-classic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2008/02/11/nokia-6120-classic/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve switched to a Nokia 6120 Classic, and I&amp;rsquo;ve switched my carrier over to Orange. I&amp;rsquo;m very happy with it: The price is right, at 0 NIS a month (if your monthly bill adds up to over 100 NIS without it, which it does). It&amp;rsquo;s very small, but has a nice screen and a respectable 2 megapixel camera. It&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;3.5G&amp;rdquo;, which means it has a very fast internet connection (I&amp;rsquo;ve clocked over 50kbyte/sec), and the Symbian S60 operating system lets me use it well - it comes with a very, very nice webkit-based browser and RSS reader, and a fast GMail client is a few clicks away.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve switched to a <a href="http://europe.nokia.com/A4399010">Nokia 6120 Classic</a>, and
I&rsquo;ve switched my carrier over to Orange. I&rsquo;m very happy with it: The price is
right, at 0 NIS a month (if your monthly bill adds up to over 100 NIS without
it, which it does). It&rsquo;s very small, but has a nice screen and a respectable 2
megapixel camera. It&rsquo;s &ldquo;3.5G&rdquo;, which means it has a very fast internet
connection (I&rsquo;ve clocked over 50kbyte/sec), and the Symbian S60 operating
system lets me use it well - it comes with a very, very nice webkit-based
browser and RSS reader, and a fast GMail client is a few clicks away.</p>
<p>Another nice feature is the built-in MP3 player - which is actually made
relevant due to the micro-SD support and included 1GB SD card. The device has a
standard USB connection (cable included, but it&rsquo;s an ordinary Mini-to-A cable),
and has a Mass Storage Device mode, so it works well with any OS. It can also
automatically text-to-speech the name of the caller (or dial by voice
recognition, which works remarkably well), which is handy when listening to
MP3s.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve only had two problems with it so far - first, when viewing a long web page
(on wikipedia, specifically), it gave an &ldquo;out of RAM&rdquo; message and rebooted. I&rsquo;m
curious as to whether there&rsquo;s a simpler, non-CSS version of Wikipedia, or a way
to get the phone to ignore the CSS - this will probably save on RAM. Another
problem I had was that the vibration feature didn&rsquo;t work until I rebooted it -
but this no longer seems to occur.</p>
<p>I wonder how well puTTy would work on this&hellip;</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Before reinstalling your server for RAID</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2007/02/26/before-reinstalling-your-server-for-raid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2007/02/26/before-reinstalling-your-server-for-raid/</guid><description>Check that the RAID it supports is actual Raid. My experience today:
Decide that secondary server should gradually become more and more primary Decide that since it has two 160GB hard drives and built-in RAID, we should use that for mirroring Mail (both!) users of the secondary server that it&amp;rsquo;ll be down for rebuilding Set up RAID array from BIOS, clearing all old information Insert installation CD Notice that installation still sees two hard drives Discover that built-in NVRaid is actually software RAID Disable built in RAID in favor of LVM, proceed to reinstall :(</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Check that the RAID it supports is actual Raid. My experience today:</p>
<ol>
<li>Decide that secondary server should gradually become more and more primary</li>
<li>Decide that since it has two 160GB hard drives and built-in RAID, we should use that for mirroring</li>
<li>Mail (both!) users of the secondary server that it&rsquo;ll be down for rebuilding</li>
<li>Set up RAID array from BIOS, clearing all old information</li>
<li>Insert installation CD</li>
<li>Notice that installation still sees two hard drives</li>
<li>Discover that built-in NVRaid is actually software RAID</li>
<li>Disable built in RAID in favor of LVM, proceed to reinstall :(</li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>