<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>hardware on Shallow and Pedantic</title><link>https://lutzky.net/tags/hardware/</link><description>Recent content in hardware on Shallow and Pedantic</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lutzky.net/tags/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PiTemp</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2021/03/14/pitemp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2021/03/14/pitemp/</guid><description>An adventure with Raspberry Pi, Golang, and small displays.</description></item><item><title>DD-WRT awesomeness</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2010/11/20/dd-wrt-awesomeness/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2010/11/20/dd-wrt-awesomeness/</guid><description>Since I&amp;rsquo;ve last posted, I&amp;rsquo;ve moved to a new apartment. First order of business - get a working internet connection. This is extra-challenging when your primary machine doesn&amp;rsquo;t even have a wireless network card.
My first hack used my trusty laptop - it has a properly working wireless card, and could connect to my roommate&amp;rsquo;s router quite easily. It runs Ubuntu, and as it turns out, that means sharing the connection was dead-simple: Right-click on the network manager icon, add a new wired connection called &amp;ldquo;Shared&amp;rdquo;, and under IPv4 settings, choose &amp;ldquo;Shared to other computers&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Android</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2010/09/04/android/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2010/09/04/android/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve finally gotten the chance to get one of those newfangled Android phones.
I&amp;rsquo;ve recently &amp;ldquo;bought&amp;rdquo; a Samsung Galaxy Android phone (the older i7500, not the newer i9000 &amp;ldquo;S&amp;rdquo;) model. It&amp;rsquo;s a seriously serious upgrade from my old Nokia 6120 Classic, and as I broke the 6120&amp;rsquo;s screen and reverted back to my trusty old Nokia 6070 (which I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even get to run the GMail app), I was quite a happy camper switching to a modern phone.</description></item><item><title>My music player has sunk</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2010/03/13/my-music-player-has-sunk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2010/03/13/my-music-player-has-sunk/</guid><description>My Meizu Mini M6 has died a tragic death as a result of being left in my shirt pocket, which in turn was - with the rest of my shirt - in the laundry. I&amp;rsquo;ve had it for three years, so this would be a good time to review.
My favorite thing about the Mini was the cost. When I bought it, it was far cheaper than comparable players, at ~400₪ for 8GB.</description></item><item><title>Broken phone screen - data rescue</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2009/10/31/broken-phone-screen-data-rescue/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2009/10/31/broken-phone-screen-data-rescue/</guid><description>Last weekend I broke my Nokia 6120&amp;rsquo;s screen. I have a military phone, which is far cheaper, so I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to keep it offline. However, being the sentimental guy that I am, I did want to save all of my contacts and SMS messages (in addition to the photos, which presented less of a problem). This proved to be a bit of a challenge without the screen working.
Usually, when you connect the phone via USB, it asks if you want &amp;ldquo;PC Suite mode&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Data Transfer mode&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Hardware doesn't like me</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2009/02/26/hardware-doesnt-like-me/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2009/02/26/hardware-doesnt-like-me/</guid><description>Whenever I try messing with hardware at home, inexplicable failures ensue. Especially when trying to help others; no good deed goes unpunished.</description></item><item><title>Whatever happened to black &amp;amp; white LCDs?</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2008/11/22/whatever-happened-to-black-white-lcds/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2008/11/22/whatever-happened-to-black-white-lcds/</guid><description>I had a Game Boy once. I could play it just about anywhere, and battery life - for the time - was great. I lost it at one point, and replaced it with a Game Gear, which sucked the life out of 6 AA batteries rather quickly. The Game Boy Color was actually decent on battery life, but since it didn&amp;rsquo;t have a backlight, you had to play it at very specific angles.</description></item><item><title>Nokia 6120 Classic</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2008/02/11/nokia-6120-classic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2008/02/11/nokia-6120-classic/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve switched to a Nokia 6120 Classic, and I&amp;rsquo;ve switched my carrier over to Orange. I&amp;rsquo;m very happy with it: The price is right, at 0 NIS a month (if your monthly bill adds up to over 100 NIS without it, which it does). It&amp;rsquo;s very small, but has a nice screen and a respectable 2 megapixel camera. It&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;3.5G&amp;rdquo;, which means it has a very fast internet connection (I&amp;rsquo;ve clocked over 50kbyte/sec), and the Symbian S60 operating system lets me use it well - it comes with a very, very nice webkit-based browser and RSS reader, and a fast GMail client is a few clicks away.</description></item><item><title>Before reinstalling your server for RAID</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2007/02/26/before-reinstalling-your-server-for-raid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2007/02/26/before-reinstalling-your-server-for-raid/</guid><description>Check that the RAID it supports is actual Raid. My experience today:
Decide that secondary server should gradually become more and more primary Decide that since it has two 160GB hard drives and built-in RAID, we should use that for mirroring Mail (both!) users of the secondary server that it&amp;rsquo;ll be down for rebuilding Set up RAID array from BIOS, clearing all old information Insert installation CD Notice that installation still sees two hard drives Discover that built-in NVRaid is actually software RAID Disable built in RAID in favor of LVM, proceed to reinstall :(</description></item></channel></rss>