<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>networking on Shallow and Pedantic</title><link>https://lutzky.net/tags/networking/</link><description>Recent content in networking on Shallow and Pedantic</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lutzky.net/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Server drawer</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2021/01/03/server-drawer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2021/01/03/server-drawer/</guid><description>A quick look at my partner-approved &amp;ldquo;server drawer&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>WFH Wifi</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2020/12/10/wfh-wifi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2020/12/10/wfh-wifi/</guid><description>My adventures in setting up wifi when working from home, working around limitations of my apartment form factor.</description></item><item><title>Home network wiring</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2011/09/04/home-network-wiring/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2011/09/04/home-network-wiring/</guid><description>&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t like wireless connections; they&amp;rsquo;re always second-best, be it in terms
of security, speed, or reliability. Here&amp;rsquo;s how my apartment looks (very
approximately):&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DD-WRT awesomeness</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2010/11/20/dd-wrt-awesomeness/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2010/11/20/dd-wrt-awesomeness/</guid><description>Since I&amp;rsquo;ve last posted, I&amp;rsquo;ve moved to a new apartment. First order of business - get a working internet connection. This is extra-challenging when your primary machine doesn&amp;rsquo;t even have a wireless network card.
My first hack used my trusty laptop - it has a properly working wireless card, and could connect to my roommate&amp;rsquo;s router quite easily. It runs Ubuntu, and as it turns out, that means sharing the connection was dead-simple: Right-click on the network manager icon, add a new wired connection called &amp;ldquo;Shared&amp;rdquo;, and under IPv4 settings, choose &amp;ldquo;Shared to other computers&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Another SSH trick</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2008/11/10/another-ssh-trick/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2008/11/10/another-ssh-trick/</guid><description>Ever have a machine you can only ssh into through another machine? It&amp;rsquo;s a very common situation in the Technion. Here&amp;rsquo;s one way to get around it: Assume you can directly ssh into alpha, and from alpha you can ssh into beta. Have the following code in your ~/.ssh/config:
Host beta Hostname 1.2.3.4 # IP Address of beta ProxyCommand ssh alpha nc -w 1 %h %p This requires you to have nc (netcat) installed on alpha.</description></item><item><title>Tunelling even more stuff over SSH</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2008/06/17/tunelling-even-more-stuff-over-ssh/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2008/06/17/tunelling-even-more-stuff-over-ssh/</guid><description>Today at the CS department of the Technion is a particularily Bad Network Day (TM) for laptop users; none of the wired connections at the farm work, and wireless doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to working for HTTP at all.
It does, however, work for SSH. Ka-ching! :)
Tunneling your browser over SSH is a pretty simple affair - SSH into somewhere which has a decent connection, and use the -D9999 flag (9999 works, but it can be any 16-bit number over 1024).</description></item><item><title>Encrypted my Wi-fi</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2007/10/28/encrypted-my-wi-fi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2007/10/28/encrypted-my-wi-fi/</guid><description>Reading some backlog on this blog, I found the following gem:
It’s a sad state of affairs that people go ahead and limit access to their wireless network. I keep mine wide open - מי שאוכל לבד, מת לבד.
Yeah&amp;hellip; not so anymore. For about four weeks (just a bit before the semester started), my net connection was working excrutiatingly slow. Now, we&amp;rsquo;re four roommates here, so we started blaming each other.</description></item><item><title>Using Jabber from within the Technion</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2007/02/27/using-jabber-from-within-the-technion/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2007/02/27/using-jabber-from-within-the-technion/</guid><description>A very neat find for those of you who want to use Jabber from within the Technion, but with your client of choice rather than a web-based one: Many Jabber servers, including Google Talk, support using Port 443 over SSL. Since the Technion does not block outbound SSL connections, this will work there as well. Be sure to mark the appropriate &amp;lsquo;Use old SSL protocol&amp;rsquo; option in your jabber client (that&amp;rsquo;s what it&amp;rsquo;s called in gaim and pidgin, at any rate).</description></item><item><title>Internet in Haifa Bay Central</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2007/02/10/internet-in-haifa-bay-central/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2007/02/10/internet-in-haifa-bay-central/</guid><description>In the Haifa Bay Central bus station (מרכזית המפרץ), it&amp;rsquo;s possible to get an internet connection. HTTPS works automatically, and setting the proxy to proxy.technion.ac.il:8080 works for HTTP. I was unsuccessful in using corkscrew to get SSH connections to tunnel over it as well, but perhaps there is still a way.</description></item><item><title>Waiting for the bus</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2007/01/25/waiting-for-the-bus/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2007/01/25/waiting-for-the-bus/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m going home for the weekend, as usual. Unfortunately, the first bus of my route comes by at highly unpredictable times - I&amp;rsquo;ve had it be an hour late on me once. There are plenty of Wi-fi networks around the station - either WPA, WEP or MAC-whitelisted&amp;hellip; fortunately, someone was using the latter long enough for me to catch him with Kismet. Thank you, stranger! :)
It&amp;rsquo;s a sad state of affairs that people go ahead and limit access to their wireless network.</description></item></channel></rss>