<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Music - Tag - Shallow and Pedantic</title><link>https://lutzky.net/tags/music/</link><description>Music - Tag - Shallow and Pedantic</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>lutzky@gmail.com (Ohad Lutzky)</managingEditor><webMaster>lutzky@gmail.com (Ohad Lutzky)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2008 11:58:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lutzky.net/tags/music/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>That "Life" category there</title><link>https://lutzky.net/posts/that-life-category-there/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2008 11:58:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Ohad Lutzky</author><guid>https://lutzky.net/posts/that-life-category-there/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I has it. Sorta.</p>
<p>A few weeks ago, the lovely <a href="http://nanuchka.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">NaNuchKa</a> visited Israel for
two and a half shows (the half-show was warming for Berry Sacharof). &ldquo;Three
shows in two weeks?&rdquo;, people ask - well, yeah. They only come once a year.
Their set is already too long to play <a href="http://youtube.com/watch?v=tn4RITTXkjw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">all the songs I
like</a>, and that&rsquo;s actually quite
excellent - new EP and all. Great stuff :) Deep Purple should be coming to
Israel this summer (holy crap!), and I need to see what I can do about getting
tickets for that.</p>
<p>This is my last semester at the Technion - then it&rsquo;s off to the military for
me. Courses for this semester are Electronic Switching Circuits (bleh&hellip;),
Signals and Systems (which is actually turning out to be quite awesome!), and
the neat Compilation Theory. After having thoroughly enjoyed <a href="http://www.cs.technion.ac.il/~biham/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Eli
Biham</a>&rsquo;s excellent Modern Cryptology last
semester, I&rsquo;m visiting (but not taking) his advanced topics course this
semester. I also have two projects: One in computer security, where we mess
with Google, and another in EE, where we try using transactional memory in
order to optimize Apache.</p>
<p>And finally - next week on Thursday, Shlomi Shaban is doing a piano show in
Haifa, just like the good old days. He was supposed to join NaNuchKa for one of
their shows, but had to cancel, so my lovely lady (who introduced me to his
work in the first place) and I haven&rsquo;t been to his shows in quite a while. It
seems that will be able to use the new <a href="http://www.egged.co.il/main.asp?lngCategoryID=6109" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">200
line</a> - part of a long
overdue project to have cheap public transportation available all night long.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>NaNuchKa</title><link>https://lutzky.net/posts/nanuchka/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2007 10:48:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Ohad Lutzky</author><guid>https://lutzky.net/posts/nanuchka/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Despite having a critical midterm Sunday, as well as being sick, I could not,
and should not have, give up on the <a href="http://myspace.com/nanuchka" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">NaNuchKa</a>
show. Some of the best music I&rsquo;ve ever heard, no doubt, and with the
unexpectedly intimate setting, I had the opportunity to get to know the truly
incredible Yula after the show. They&rsquo;re playing in Tel-Aviv today, at the
Koltura, where I was supposed to&hellip; Fantastic music, at any rate. Keep your
ears open!</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Some music posted to myspace</title><link>https://lutzky.net/posts/some-music-posted-to-myspace/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2007 22:44:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Ohad Lutzky</author><guid>https://lutzky.net/posts/some-music-posted-to-myspace/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Recording this morning was excellent! Awesome studio, not expensive at all, and
a whole lot of fun. We&rsquo;ve posted one song at <a href="http://myspace.com/switchblade777" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">our myspace
page</a>, and it seems that Lior has found an
apt name for the CD (hint) ;)</p>
<p>For those of you who don&rsquo;t want to visit Myspace (can&rsquo;t blame you), here&rsquo;s the
song we posted, as well as an extra track (my personal favorite), Falsely
Accused.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="/posts/some-music-posted-to-myspace/Switchblade%20-%20Old%20School%20Daze%20-%2002%20-%20The%20Deal.mp3" rel="">The deal</a></li>
<li><a href="/posts/some-music-posted-to-myspace/Switchblade%20-%20Old%20School%20Daze%20-%2006%20-%20Falsely%20Accused.mp3" rel="">Falsely Accused</a></li>
</ul>
<p>I really want to point out the <strong>incredible</strong> recording studio we used - it&rsquo;s a
place called MIXסולידי in Tel Hanania. The man charged us very little, and the
equipment and space are excellent. As you can probably tell, those are just
demo recordings - recorded &ldquo;live&rdquo;, with plenty of mistakes, and with very
minimal balance and sound tweaking. We&rsquo;ll definitely be going back there to
record a more serious version.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Some band stuff</title><link>https://lutzky.net/posts/some-band-stuff/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2007 22:20:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Ohad Lutzky</author><guid>https://lutzky.net/posts/some-band-stuff/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>This Saturday we&rsquo;re going to record our material, and hopefully a cover we&rsquo;ve
been working on - Venom&rsquo;s excellent &ldquo;School Daze&rdquo;. We took some photos
yesterday, visible here:
<a href="http://www.myspace.com/switchblade777/photos/albums/my-photos/826538" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">http://www.myspace.com/switchblade777/photos/albums/my-photos/826538</a><sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup></p>
<p>We have a show at the Koltura Club on July 12th.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup></p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Link modified to accomodate mists of time.&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>Poster lost in the mists of time, show ended up being cancelled at the last moment.&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></description></item><item><title>Myspace sucks</title><link>https://lutzky.net/posts/myspace-sucks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2007 14:26:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Ohad Lutzky</author><guid>https://lutzky.net/posts/myspace-sucks/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Life is good, for the most part. And as a technology enthusiast, there are many
new and cool things to see online. For example, there&rsquo;s the new
<a href="http://schools.whatsup.org.il" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Schools</a> site, part of the Vaya project which
helps Israeli schools use Linux; this site uses the up-and-coming
<a href="http://lahak.python-hosting.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Lahak</a> CMS, built on the Django framework,
and looks very promising to the eyes of the bidi-lingual webmaster.</p>
<p>However, some things just plain suck. One of them is myspace; today, in an
attempt to make it more legible, I found that <a href="http://myspace.com/switchblade777" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">My Band&rsquo;s
Page</a> implements all of its styling changes
by a &ldquo;style&rdquo; tag hidden within the &ldquo;Members&rdquo; text block. Myspace doesn&rsquo;t filter
this out - nor does it provide any other means of changing the styling. This,
combined with myspace&rsquo;s horrid administration interface, makes editing
incredible unwieldy. I&rsquo;m considering opening another Wordpress site for the
band here on this server&hellip;</p>
<p>And on that topic - Wordpress 2.2 is out. Shinier. Faster. Built-in support for
sidebar modules. And K2 broke :(. I love K2&hellip; Even though now that sidebars
are implemented, the only thing I really need is a very simple template that
allows me an ordinary, rectangular logo. <strong>Update:</strong> I didn&rsquo;t even notice, but
the excellent K2 guys released a fix. However, it seems that when you copy the
plugin they created directly, it inadvertantly adds a space to the end of the
file - and PHP proceeds to barf. Hard to believe people still use this junk to
develop websites&hellip; They should use <a href="http://railsenvy.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">other junk</a>.</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>On the matter of a really long vacation</title><link>https://lutzky.net/posts/on-the-matter-of-a-really-long-vacation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2007 22:14:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Ohad Lutzky</author><guid>https://lutzky.net/posts/on-the-matter-of-a-really-long-vacation/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>By now I&rsquo;ve lost count of how long ago my last class was. The strike has begun
immediately after passover, and is certainly beginning to take its toll. For
one thing, I have no homework deadlines - a rare situation indeed for the
Technion student. Furthermore, contemplations are rising about whether or not
this coming summer semester will be held, as the current semester will most
likely leak into it. This is of special interest to me, as I&rsquo;m behind on my
degree, which is problematic because of my military scholarship. This is
shaping up to be the second time in which, while I&rsquo;ve been authorized by the
military to take a summer semester for completion, I am not able to. However,
one cannot trivially dismiss this strike; in a country which is known worldwide
mostly for its technological exports and frequent bloodbaths, one shouldn&rsquo;t
take the matter of tuition lightly.</p>
<p>The vacation was not, however, boring - I got to spend a lot of time with my
lovely girlfriend, a chance to see friends I have not seen in a long time, and
a lot of posts racked up in various forums. The vacation actually expanded far
enough to contain independence day, so I managed to experience the closest
thing to a hangover I&rsquo;d ever had (But that was some great scotch). Actually,
independence day could have been truly superb; the whole thing got me thinking
about what the perfect night out would be: It&rsquo;s obviously best with my
girlfriend. It would probably start with a rock show of sorts, continue with
food and beer, and end in my girlfriend&rsquo;s bed. Better yet - if I&rsquo;m <em>in</em> the
show. Better still - if there&rsquo;s no reason to get up early the following day.</p>
<p>Another item of interest is that I&rsquo;ve joined a band. Hopefully I&rsquo;ll be able to
keep up the 3-hours-on-Saturday rehearsals. It&rsquo;s a &ldquo;Trash Metal&rdquo; band which has
evidently had really bad experience with bass players. Unfortunately, we seem
to have a <a href="http://myspace.com/switchblade777" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">myspace page</a>. It looks&hellip;
myspaceish. However, I really think the group has potential, as well as
excellent influences. Furthermore, I&rsquo;m an attention whore :D. Hopefully I&rsquo;ll be
able to help influence the band into more of a heavy-metal direction by
harassing them with melodic basslines.</p>
<p>Very little geek news this time, other than the fact that <a href="http://ubuntu.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Feisty
Fawn</a> is out. My verdict - get it. It&rsquo;s awesome. Period.
Suspend works much better, NetworkManager is now installed by default, a lot of
things have really been polished, and - can you believe it - Sudoku :)! If you
already run Ubuntu, I&rsquo;d advise against using the update manager - it works, but
it takes a long time, and cannot run unattended. Also, a word of caution to
server admins though - sqlite3 is the new default, so if you have sqlite2
databases you&rsquo;ll need to convert them (use the sqlite and sqlite3 binaries to
do this) - otherwise you&rsquo;ll get &ldquo;file is not a database, or is encrypted&rdquo;
errors.</p>
<p>Whew - that&rsquo;s much better. My thoughts have been depleted into the bits and
bytes before you. I&rsquo;ll just <a href="http://gadial.net" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">plug a friend&rsquo;s blog</a> and hit
the publish button now ;)</p>
]]></description></item><item><title>Bass guitar</title><link>https://lutzky.net/posts/bass-guitar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2007 21:17:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Ohad Lutzky</author><guid>https://lutzky.net/posts/bass-guitar/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I brought my Fender Squier Jazz Bass up to my Technion apartment. I hope it
won&rsquo;t have too much of an adverse effect on my studying&hellip; playing it (loud) is
great for stress, and I&rsquo;m taking a jazz improvisation course next semester.</p>
<p>By the way - if any of you record with one of these, I highly recommend
<a href="http://ardour.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Arour</a>, using a low-pass LADSPA filter. Also, activating
both pickups on about 80% does wonders against hum if you connect directly.</p>
]]></description></item></channel></rss>