<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>music on Shallow and Pedantic</title><link>https://lutzky.net/tags/music/</link><description>Recent content in music on Shallow and Pedantic</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lutzky.net/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>That "Life" category there</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2008/07/11/that-life-category-there/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2008/07/11/that-life-category-there/</guid><description>I has it. Sorta.
A few weeks ago, the lovely NaNuchKa visited Israel for two and a half shows (the half-show was warming for Berry Sacharof). &amp;ldquo;Three shows in two weeks?&amp;rdquo;, people ask - well, yeah. They only come once a year. Their set is already too long to play all the songs I like, and that&amp;rsquo;s actually quite excellent - new EP and all. Great stuff :) Deep Purple should be coming to Israel this summer (holy crap!</description></item><item><title>NaNuchKa</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2007/07/27/nanuchka/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2007/07/27/nanuchka/</guid><description>Despite having a critical midterm Sunday, as well as being sick, I could not, and should not have, give up on the NaNuchKa show. Some of the best music I&amp;rsquo;ve ever heard, no doubt, and with the unexpectedly intimate setting, I had the opportunity to get to know the truly incredible Yula after the show. They&amp;rsquo;re playing in Tel-Aviv today, at the Koltura, where I was supposed to&amp;hellip; Fantastic music, at any rate.</description></item><item><title>Some music posted to myspace</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2007/06/02/some-music-posted-to-myspace/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2007/06/02/some-music-posted-to-myspace/</guid><description>Recording this morning was excellent! Awesome studio, not expensive at all, and a whole lot of fun. We&amp;rsquo;ve posted one song at our myspace page, and it seems that Lior has found an apt name for the CD (hint) ;)
For those of you who don&amp;rsquo;t want to visit Myspace (can&amp;rsquo;t blame you), here&amp;rsquo;s the song we posted, as well as an extra track (my personal favorite), Falsely Accused.
The Deal Falsely Accused I really want to point out the incredible recording studio we used - it&amp;rsquo;s a place called MIXסולידי in Tel Hanania.</description></item><item><title>Some band stuff</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2007/05/31/some-band-stuff/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2007/05/31/some-band-stuff/</guid><description>This Saturday we&amp;rsquo;re going to record our material, and hopefully a cover we&amp;rsquo;ve been working on - Venom&amp;rsquo;s excellent &amp;ldquo;School Daze&amp;rdquo;. We took some photos yesterday, visible here: http://www.myspace.com/switchblade777/photos/albums/my-photos/8265381
We have a show at the Koltura Club on July 12th.2
Link modified to accomodate mists of time.&amp;#160;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;
Poster lost in the mists of time, show ended up being cancelled at the last moment.&amp;#160;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;</description></item><item><title>Myspace sucks</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2007/05/17/myspace-sucks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2007/05/17/myspace-sucks/</guid><description>Life is good, for the most part. And as a technology enthusiast, there are many new and cool things to see online. For example, there&amp;rsquo;s the new Schools site, part of the Vaya project which helps Israeli schools use Linux; this site uses the up-and-coming Lahak CMS, built on the Django framework, and looks very promising to the eyes of the bidi-lingual webmaster.
However, some things just plain suck. One of them is myspace; today, in an attempt to make it more legible, I found that My Band&amp;rsquo;s Page implements all of its styling changes by a &amp;ldquo;style&amp;rdquo; tag hidden within the &amp;ldquo;Members&amp;rdquo; text block.</description></item><item><title>On the matter of a really long vacation</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2007/04/24/on-the-matter-of-a-really-long-vacation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2007/04/24/on-the-matter-of-a-really-long-vacation/</guid><description>By now I&amp;rsquo;ve lost count of how long ago my last class was. The strike has begun immediately after passover, and is certainly beginning to take its toll. For one thing, I have no homework deadlines - a rare situation indeed for the Technion student. Furthermore, contemplations are rising about whether or not this coming summer semester will be held, as the current semester will most likely leak into it. This is of special interest to me, as I&amp;rsquo;m behind on my degree, which is problematic because of my military scholarship.</description></item><item><title>Bass guitar</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2007/02/25/bass-guitar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2007/02/25/bass-guitar/</guid><description>I brought my Fender Squier Jazz Bass up to my Technion apartment. I hope it won&amp;rsquo;t have too much of an adverse effect on my studying&amp;hellip; playing it (loud) is great for stress, and I&amp;rsquo;m taking a jazz improvisation course next semester.
By the way - if any of you record with one of these, I highly recommend Arour, using a low-pass LADSPA filter. Also, activating both pickups on about 80% does wonders against hum if you connect directly.</description></item></channel></rss>