<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on Shallow and Pedantic</title><link>https://lutzky.net/pages/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on Shallow and Pedantic</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 21:52:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lutzky.net/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Linux stuff</title><link>https://lutzky.net/linux-stuff/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 21:52:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/linux-stuff/</guid><description>Here is an assortment of Linux-related tips and tricks.
If you&amp;rsquo;re tired of hitting your SSH password over and over again, you might want to take a look at this guide: SSH Public Key Authentication.
If you&amp;rsquo;re a Technion student taking the Matam course, you should definitely check out the Matam Guide.
Here is a list of lectures I&amp;rsquo;ve given in Haifux:
Lightning Talks 2005 (w/Many others) LIRC - Infrared Remote Control (w/Alon Altman) WiFi in Linux The VIM Editor for beginners (Rerun of Shlomi&amp;rsquo;s lecture) FatNS - How to develop a DNS forensics tool (w/Boaz Goldstein) Linux for CS Students - a Primer Linux for CS Students - Debugging If you&amp;rsquo;re with a russian keyboard and need a stress sign, try /russian-stress.</description></item><item><title>SSH public key authentication</title><link>https://lutzky.net/linux-stuff/ssh-public-key-authentication/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 21:51:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/linux-stuff/ssh-public-key-authentication/</guid><description>If you find yourself logging into SSH servers a lot, you might find this tip useful - you&amp;rsquo;ll only need to type your password once per session. But first, let&amp;rsquo;s set the default username (so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to tell SSH what user you are every time):
$ cd ~ $ mkdir .ssh $ chmod 700 .ssh $ cat &amp;gt;&amp;gt; .ssh/config Host t2.technion.ac.il User slutzky Ctrl-D $ Now, create a public/private key pair for SSH, like so:</description></item><item><title>Russian stress mark</title><link>https://lutzky.net/russian-stress/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/russian-stress/</guid><description> This is a handy little page for copying the stress mark (acute mark) to clipboard. Useful if your Russian keyboard doesn't support it.
́ function copyIt() { document.getElementById('copyBuffer').select(); document.execCommand('copy'); } Copy</description></item></channel></rss>