<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>show downloading on Shallow and Pedantic</title><link>https://lutzky.net/tags/show-downloading/</link><description>Recent content in show downloading on Shallow and Pedantic</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lutzky.net/tags/show-downloading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Weird permission issues with tvnamer</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2014/01/05/investigate/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2014/01/05/investigate/</guid><description>Distinguishing &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->EPERM&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> vs &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->EACCESS&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->, and how that helps debug file manipulation scripts.</description></item><item><title>The show downloading stack - part n+1</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2011/12/15/the-show-downloading-stack-part-n1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2011/12/15/the-show-downloading-stack-part-n1/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve already mentioned my show downloading stack on this blog. It&amp;rsquo;s changed a bit since - I now use Transmission rather than rtorrent, as it has the excellent transmission-daemon package which has it acting exactly the way I like (without using screen). Also, it now E-mails me when a torrent is done downloading. So while this may be how TV works for you:
Notice that a new episode is out Torrent it Wait for the download to finish Watch it &amp;hellip;this is how TV works for me now:</description></item><item><title>Loving the new Totem</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2009/10/10/loving-the-new-totem/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2009/10/10/loving-the-new-totem/</guid><description>Totem is Gnome&amp;rsquo;s built-in media player, and it really annoyed me in previous versions, and had me switching to VLC. However, the version included in the Ubuntu 9.10 release candidate has two features which are very important, in my opinion. The first feature is smooth graphical integration with compositing managers (such as compiz). In previous versions, as well as VLC, once you fullscreen the window, moving the mouse (which causes the cursor and the partial interface to appear) causes a very annoying flicker.</description></item><item><title>My show downloading stack</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2009/09/05/my-show-downloading-stack/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2009/09/05/my-show-downloading-stack/</guid><description>I love watching TV, and hate it. Regular show schedules are horrible, commercial breaks are annoying, and the ability to rewind is very important. I love Hot&amp;rsquo;s VOD service (and happily pay to watch the shows I enjoy), but my true favorite for getting my entertainment is everyone&amp;rsquo;s favorite not-a-dumptruck, the internet. In this post, I will describe how I do it.
Everything I describe in this post can be done using miro.</description></item><item><title>Alright, American Dad!</title><link>https://lutzky.net/2007/01/23/alright-american-dad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lutzky.net/2007/01/23/alright-american-dad/</guid><description>Just finished downloading an episode of American Dad off Bittorrent. TV has ancient episodes of Family Guy. Took about an hour though&amp;hellip; I tells ya, I&amp;rsquo;d pay for this kind of service if it were faster&amp;hellip; ;)</description></item></channel></rss>